<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-05T12:20:12-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Benjamin Cai</title><author><name>Benjamin Cai</name><email>main@benjamincai.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Life1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/04/Life1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life1" /><published>2025-10-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-10-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/10/04/Life1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/04/Life1/"><![CDATA[<p>Hey, I don’t know if anybody reads this thing. I have not tracked analytics in weeks. Oh well. I like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">talking</code> or whatever this functions as. I wouldn’t call it <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">writing</code> since it’s not really as purposeful as I’d like, but it’s also clearly not <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">talking</code>. Idk.</p>

<p>Point is, I kinda like just sitting down and putting the stuff I’ve been thinking about down (down used twice there sounds weird). After all, if you yourself won’t like listening to your thoughts, who else will?</p>

<p>Think of this as just a description of what’s been going on and how I’ve been adjusting to college.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="the-bad">the bad</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/Life1_2.jpeg" alt="stsdfs" title="The very very bad" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEP, I may have thrown</code></p>

<p>So uh, worst part is, I don’t even think the content was that <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">hard</code>. It’s just, I mean, I don’t want to use it as an <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">excuse</code>, but like I was <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">deathly</code> sick while taking the exam. I came in with a facemask because breathing in normal air hurt. My eyes were burning the entire time. My head was on fire (not in a good way). It was pretty bad. Still though, rather disappointing that I performed so well. I’d expect myself to still perform better even under worse circumstances.</p>

<p>The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">68</code> is pretty bad. But the bright side is that it is very much recoverable. I’ve looked down on those who cling to something impossible so fiercely in the past, but like, in this case, it is very much not <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">impossible</code>. Professor, who is a very good lecturer and cool guy, grades on a z score so my <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">68</code> actually becomes a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">B</code>. That’s still pretty bad, but like, if I drop outlier z scores on the next couple exams, I should be fine. I’ll just make sure to study and hopefully not get sick. I’m not looking forward to the Spring when my allergies kick in again. I hate allergies. My number one opp.</p>

<p>The most scary thing is that, I think, even if I was at a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">not-sick</code> performance level, I still wouldn’t have dropped higher than a 90. There were actual, real mistakes that I made. One example, is that I didn’t know that tree diagrams branches might need the given for a probability depending on the situation when drawing them. I mean, I still get to the right answer, but if asked to draw a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">tree diagram</code>, that is a mistake. Everything else – I think – would’ve been correct had I no been a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dead man</code> walking while taking the exam.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/postImages/Life1_21.jpeg" alt="stsdfs" title="c" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">fun</code></p>

<p>On the topic of content though, I love <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">probability</code>. I mean, the content is just very interesting. I don’t really know how else to put it.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="the-kinda-bright-side">The kinda Bright Side</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/Life1_3.jpeg" alt="stsdfs" title="light" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kinda light</code></p>

<p>Most classes are actually a lot easier than I expected. I mean, I did drop a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">68</code>, but like…yeah no, I kinda just failed the test. Oh well. Hopefully, it works out <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">fine</code>.</p>

<p>Uh, data structures is fine. The test was better than I thought. Probability is somewhat fine. Oh, my schedule. It’s, uh, probability, discrete, data structures, vector calc, and a first year signature course. Discrete and vector calc have literally only been <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">review</code> of high school classes so it’s kinda hard for me to comment on difficulty. Yeah. Still better than high school because we move faster though.</p>

<p>I <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">surprisingly</code> think I have more free time in college than high school. That’s crazy to think about. Probably most of it comes from having less class time, but like, the homework is also less. Crazy. If I get less than an <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">A</code> in probability though, you guys can all <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">laugh</code> at me. I mean, that will be entirely my fault and my pride will be pretty <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">funny</code> to look at. I hope, if that happens, I temper my <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pride</code>, become <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">humble</code>, and accept the mistake in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ego</code>.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="people">people</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/Life1_4.png" alt="stsdfs" title="people" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">interesting people</code></p>

<p>The people here are… <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">interesting</code>. I don’t know. What I like is that I don’t feel a need to talk to random people. I mean, I sometimes do, but like it feels fine to just do stuff <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">alone</code>. In high school, that was kinda different. Doing stuff alone just felt lonely. In college though, it’s just like, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ok cool</code>.</p>

<p>Also, it’s been insanely hard to keep some friend groups from high school alive. Like genuinely impossible <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">tough</code>. Like to the point where I’m down to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">give up</code>.</p>

<p>The college people I’ve met have been cool and chill though. Nothing much to say there.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="piano-chess-and-writing">Piano, Chess, and Writing</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/Life1_5.png" alt="stsdfs" title="offf, oh i mean t ooooof" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sad no more practice</code></p>

<p>I believe I’ve wrote about this before, but I really like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">piano</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">chess</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">writing</code>. However, surprisingly, I’ve found it rather hard to keep those hobbies alive. I mean, I go to the chess club (it’s like sectioned off in a mall and feels extremely <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sketch</code>, but the people are cool), but I haven’t really <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">enjoyed</code> chess to the same extent I used to. Idk, it’s weird. I liked OTB tournaments quite a lot (I’ve gone to two since coming to UT), and if anything, that’s become more true. While I never really liked online chess, I would still find enjoyment in it and play to get better. However, I’ve found that instead of doing a chess puzzle when I have some downtime in a class or on a walk, I just read <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Apple News</code>. It is very sad. I’m old now. Wtf. Might be time to pass the torch on. That’s sad.</p>

<p>I came into UT Austin wanting to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">double major</code> in Piano. After seeing the Interactive Degree Audit (showing me the needed classes), and realizing that about 0 classes overlap, piano requires 8 semesters of ensemble (I have 0 right now), and there are about 60 hours of theory classes, I have given up. I mean, I think the classes are possible in some <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">alternate</code> world, but the 8 semesters of ensemble already means I’d be graduating a semester <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">late</code>. I came into college wanting to graduate <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">early</code>. 
I’ve also finally found a good piano. I used to take the long walk to the Butler Hall of Music (which is about a 20 minute endeavor in 90 degree weather), but now I’ve discovered a Grand Piano right in the lobby of my dorm. I probably should’ve used that earlier. I’m smart. It’s kinda a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">scuffed</code> piano, but like it’s also good. I sincerely want to make sure that I can perform the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4 Ballades</code> well. In my opinion, the 4 Ballades are the pinnacle of Chopin’s writing (actually maybe not, but they’re the best series), so I think being able to perform all 4 in one go would be really, really <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cool</code>. Yep, just <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cool</code>.</p>

<p>As for writing, it’s always been kind of on and off, and I’ve had trouble sticking to a stable, daily regiment. At the same time though, I’ve always maintained some kind of practice. Though, for some reason, I’ve just had a hard time keeping that up in college. Luckily, there’s a cool <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">LLC</code> (which is like kind of an org) that’s about writing which does weekly things. That means, at the very least, I can somewhat keep up weekly stories of some sort.</p>

<p>The most surprising thing for me is that each of these three hobbies have not even dropped off in output due to less time. No, strangely, it’s not that. I can’t actually seem to pinpoint the exact reason, but my belief is that it’s something to do with the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">environment</code>. I’ve long held the belief that environment dictates a lot of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">routine</code>, so perhaps, by moving to the dorm room as my main home instead of say my computer desk at home (I know very <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sad</code> main home for both), I’ve lost some routine that kept up my hobbies. Rather interesting.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="some-ending-thoughts-as-a-time-capsule">Some ending thoughts as a time capsule</h2>

<p><img src="/assets/postImages/Life1_6.png" alt="stsdfs" title="time capsule" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">trust me, when i'm 89 on my deathbed, imma look at ts</code></p>

<p>This stuff will be more <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">all-over-the-place</code> than anything else.</p>

<p>Firstly, I think I came in wanting to do too many things. I got rejected from <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Longhorn Developers</code> (like a UT organization for developing stuff), but at the same time, I’m not sure how fun nor how much time I’d be willing to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">commit</code> to that. I have so many things I want to get good at – like CAD, 3d printing stuff, robotics, math, proofs, business – and at the end of the day, I think I’m very <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">stretched out</code>. This is also me just not wanting the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sour</code> grapes though (if you know that <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">allegory</code>).</p>

<p>I have some serious <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">math</code> commitments as part of a Directed Reading Program which has been very fun (mainly due to my great <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mentor</code>). I also have some robotics stuff I want to do (and that I owe my <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Combat Robotics</code> team to do). And then, I also just have this <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">subdueing</code> desire to start some business. Idk why though. Yeah, I’ve been kinda down from getting rejected from LHD. Perhaps, that was my mistake for only applying to a few <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">orgs</code>. Some other people I’ve talked to have told me that they applied to over <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">20</code>, and then I just think “wow, that’s crazy”.</p>

<p>Career fair was fun. I only handed out <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4</code> resumes though. Everybody else handed out like 20. The people I talked to there were all super cool and nice (plus our conversations were fun). My lexicon has been gradually diminishing in complexity. Disappointing.</p>

<p>Also, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"> is something that I never go that deep into. I only really used it with friends. Recently though, I've found that it's very good at explaining certain concepts. I treat it as like a </code>TA` that can explain a mathematical proof or a simpler form of Google for documentation. Like, you can ask it to explain what a Hessian matrix represents or whether a Java data structure has a .contains method.</p>

<p>I still waste too much time on <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YouTube</code>. I have so many personal projects I also want to do. I’m stretched in too many directions. But like, at the same time, that’s what I like!</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="to-conclude-i-will-conclude-by-saying-that-in-conclusion">To conclude, I will conclude, by saying that in conclusion…</h2>

<p>Shoot, I normally end these on a depressing note. Alright, I got this. I know how to end this on a depressing note.</p>

<p>I was thinking about the people I talked to in high school and realized that I will never see any of them who didn’t go to UT Austin again. That’s pretty depressing.</p>

<p>There are also one friend I have that’s out of state who I used to talk with a lot online (mainly talked in person before). Now, we’ve kinda stopped too.</p>

<p>Man, friendships suck. Too much <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">feeling</code>. I don’t quite like it. But like, at the same time, it’s gratifying to talk to people. Maybe, I just start talking to random people and use that to get my need for social interaction. There’s no commitment that way.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="i-played-in-the-ccl-and-threw-multiple-positions-the-goat">I played in the CCL and threw multiple positions (THE GOAT)</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/Life1_7.png" alt="asdf" title="The goat" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">I will write a post on this tomorrow!!!</code></p>]]></content><author><name>Benjamin Cai</name><email>main@benjamincai.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey, I don’t know if anybody reads this thing. I have not tracked analytics in weeks. Oh well. I like talking or whatever this functions as. I wouldn’t call it writing since it’s not really as purposeful as I’d like, but it’s also clearly not talking. Idk.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/Life1_1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/Life1_1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Summer Yet</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/31/Best-Summer-Yet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Summer Yet" /><published>2025-08-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-08-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/31/Best-Summer-Yet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/31/Best-Summer-Yet/"><![CDATA[<p>Just hit <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Akali 3</code> to win a lobby. I’m the goat. Anyways, this was a pretty fun summer. I liked it quite a bit. Mainly because of where I worked but also some other stuff. - <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">8/20/2025</code></p>

<p>This summer, I spent my time at a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">job</code>. At first glance, that sounds rather sad. I’m spending the last summer before college working rather than…whatever else people do. Sometimes, I like working though. In this case, I think applying for the internship I did was one of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">best</code> decisions I’ve ever made. That’s a rather <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">strong</code> statement. But, I also think I can back it up.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="how-it-started">How it started</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/BestSummerYet2.png" alt="stsdfs" title="Application" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">The application header</code></p>

<p>During high school, I think I was really concerned with doing <em>something</em> this summer. What I mean by that is that I wanted to gain some skills and experience – partially because I wanted to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bolster</code> my resume prior to freshman year and partially because I felt I had not accomplished anything <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">significant</code> yet.</p>

<p>I first heard of the place I worked <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">(ARL)</code> after seeing the program product, student reports, on my school’s college counselor’s desk. ARL stands for Applied Research Laboratories, and since ARL is a government organization, I won’t go into too much <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">detail</code>.</p>

<p>Basically, while talking to my college counselor about college applications, the ARL student reports caught my <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">eye</code>. I asked my college counselor about it, and he explained the program to me. Then, I thought a bit, realized it was far too early to apply since it was only <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">September</code>, stored it in my head, and told myself that I would apply in a couple of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">months</code>.</p>

<p>I don’t recall the exact time frame, but at same point in time around <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring</code>, I opened the application, decided it was too long and too difficult, and put it off until the week before (at least my <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">procrastination</code> did not leave it until the day before!).</p>

<p>I remember very clearly that I finished writing the application during lunch in a teacher’s classroom. After finishing, I put off turning it in until a couple days before. Then, I turned it in, and that was that. Quite the interesting story.</p>

<hr />
<h2 id="what-the-fun-thing-was">What the fun thing was</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/BestSummerYet3.png" alt="stsdfs" title="heatmap" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Literally just a matplotlib heatmap, nothing of importance here</code></p>

<p>Ok, now for the actually interesting part. I don’t know how much I can actually share – I’m pretty sure I can share all of it – but at the same time, I will veer on the side of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">caution</code>. At a high level, I worked on speeding up signal acquisition using <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">GPUs</code>. Signal acquisition is one of the first steps for GPS location solving, and for those that don’t know, GPUs can make certain operations <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">really, really fast</code>.</p>

<p>The fun part was the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">math</code>. It’s that <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">simple</code>. There’s so much math that underlies GPS and signal processing as a whole that I legitimately believe I could fill up <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">multiple notebooks</code> with just what I learned in a single week at ARL.</p>

<p>I can definitely share this: my favorite math part was manipulating <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">FFTs</code> in equations. I’d heard of FFTs before working at ARL but only in a very abstract <em>something, something, frequency</em> kind of way. At ARL though, I learned in much <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">greater detail</code> what they are and actually saw all the math I’d learned in high school put into real-world use (which was just <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">insane</code> to me).</p>

<p>Frankly, I’d always believed in a sort of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">math is cool</code> but only really as a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">foundational structure</code>. What I mean by that is that mathematicians and researchers set up grand advances in human innovation, but the actual impact on people’s lives is brought about not by math but by <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">scale</code> more than anything. The clearest example that I would use to justify this idea is in AI. AI is only possible due to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">linear algebra and calculus</code>. However, technologies like ChatGPT or AlphaFold are only here because of the massive scale of data along with the massive amount of money that huge tech companies can invest. I’m very not knowledgeable in history and AI, but I’m fairly confident that the math for modern AI was present <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">20 years ago</code> if not even further back.</p>

<p>At ARL though, I saw <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">math</code> quite clearly being used to discover things and identify how things would change in a <em>not-industry-scale</em> but also not <em>pure research</em> kind of way (using the word <strong>things</strong> to stay vague).</p>

<hr />
<h2 id="what-i-helped-with-a-lot-lot-of-help-create">What I helped (with a lot, lot of help) create</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/BestSummerYet4.png" alt="stsdfs" title="gps" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Surprisingly accurate, a much better explanation than anything I could come up with</code></p>

<p>Let me make clear, I was <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">hard carried</code> by my supervisors and the guy I worked with. While I think I contributed a lot and wrote a good <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">majority</code> of the code, without the people who helped me, I don’t think I could’ve even created a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">basic</code> signal acquisition program. All of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">math</code> was taught to me by them, most of the programming <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">knowledge</code> was imparted by them as well, and what to look into for <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">optimizations</code> was essentially fed to me by them too. All in all, I am <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">infinitely</code> thankful for their help.</p>

<p>The end product that I ended up creating (from <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">scratch</code> which I think is the coolest part!) was a program that was able to do continuous signal acquisition for GPS. Extremely vague, but that’s so I don’t accidentally do something not good. It was a <strong>20x</strong> speed up though (mostly due to the GPU) which is extremely cool.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="to-conclude-i-will-conclude-by-saying-that-in-conclusion">To conclude, I will conclude, by saying that in conclusion…</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/BestSummerYet5.png" alt="stsdfs" title="gpu" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">GPUs!</code></p>

<p>Fantastic experience. My summer was made more fun by meeting with some friends that I hadn’t seen in a long time, but to be honest, it was hard carried by this experience.</p>

<p>Anyways, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Akali</code> fell off hard. So, I can’t play Akali in TFT anymore. Sad.</p>

<p>I think I can confidently say that this was my best summer. Hopefully, they keep getting <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">better!</code></p>

<hr />

<h2 id="college">College</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/BestSummerYet6.jpeg" alt="stsdfs" title="gpu" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">UT Austin turtles</code></p>

<p>I took so long to finish this post (mostly cause I was reading <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">One Piece Colored</code> version) that college has already started. It has been rather fun! I have to say that I was pleasantly surprised by how <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">fun</code> college has been. It has been very <em>fun</em>.</p>

<p>I feel so <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">productive</code> in college. It’s strange but staying in a dorm and only having my laptop instead of my desktop setup at home makes me want to do work rather than <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">waste time</code> watching YouTube. It’s very <strong>fun</strong>!</p>

<p>I don’t like the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">tone shift</code> in this post where it sounds happy now. So, I will end in such a principled manner as to conclude by saying that time passes all of us by. It is up to us to ensure that our time is spent in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">happiness</code> or in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">legacy</code>. So, choose which one you desire for both is an <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">impossibility</code> afforded to the very few lucky ones.</p>

<p>Also, the layout image that says <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ARL</code> is dead wrong!</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="couldnt-remember-the-position-but-what-should-white-play">Couldn’t remember the position, but what should White play?</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/BestSummerYet7.png" alt="asdf" title="Nice little position from a tournament on June 6, 2025" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">I've been playing a lot of chess games against people down a queen to make it more fun. It's kind of disrespectful, but at the same time, it's really boring to play against someone not at my skill level when we have equal material. Like, imagine fighting a toddler. That's just boring.</code></p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">This position is supposed to be from a game I played with a friend I went to the mall with. That person is now in another state far from where I am but is what it is. Either way, my advice if you're starting down a Queen is to hedgehog, then attack, then hope to somehow gain back some material for the endgame. You can usually scam endgames. Iirc, in this game, my attack led to checkmate, but I remembered this position wrong, so is what it is.</code></p>]]></content><author><name>Benjamin Cai</name><email>main@benjamincai.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just hit Akali 3 to win a lobby. I’m the goat. Anyways, this was a pretty fun summer. I liked it quite a bit. Mainly because of where I worked but also some other stuff. - 8/20/2025]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/BestSummerYet1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/BestSummerYet1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Professional Fumbler</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/19/Professional-Fumbler/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Professional Fumbler" /><published>2025-08-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-08-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/19/Professional-Fumbler</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/19/Professional-Fumbler/"><![CDATA[<p>This tournament is probably the last one I go to for a long time. The unique point about this tournament was that I did not play all that up, meaning that most people I played were below me in rating. I actually don’t really like that. It’s kinda weird to play people under. I like being the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">underdog!</code> Having the handicap makes it much easier because then even if you fail, it’s expected. I think I could’ve won all my first game and then I would’ve had a chance to go <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">5/5</code> but it is what it is yk. Man, that first game really makes me disappointed in myself. I had the much better position but then I hard threw. Is what it is. That’s why you don’t go low on time.</p>

<p>Anyways, college is starting soon. That should be <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">fun</code>. Also, the caption of “pivot to Scammer” is a reference to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">TFT</code>, the greatest game ever made. I have become sorely addicted to TFT and can only pray that such an addiction will dissipate before college starts. Speaking of which, I just hit two four costs on 3-1 at level 5. That’s crazy. yeah, I’m playing TFT while writing this (hard forcing Akali because Worth the Wait Kennen, degenerate behavior). I am not addicted. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Trust!</code></p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-1-benjamin-cai-black-1---0">Game 1 Benjamin Cai Black (1 - 0)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/YkIdtku7/rt7dvXmx" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>This game was <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">60 + 10</code> so like I kinda messed up time management.</p>

<p>Yeah, I saw Nc3 (move 2), and thought it would be a Grand Prix game (the theory of which I do not know). I should probably learn Grand Prix theory before it’s too late. Oh well.</p>

<p>I kinda messed up the opening really bad. D4 (move 9) is just a horrible move because of Ne4 which I somehow just completely missed. Yeah, I missed a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">FORWARD</code> knight move. My cap might legitimately be <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2000</code>.</p>

<p>But then, my opponent made a couple mistakes and I scammed out the advantage (computer says drawn after opponent goes down exchange but like who’s tryna play that position against the two minor pieces, not me!). My point being, after Kg8 (move 17), I am kind of completely fine. I think I’m probably the only one playing for the win there.</p>

<p>I cook the position for a while and get a pretty significant positional advantage but Rxe5 (move 29) happens – keep in mind I had like 7 seconds here for some reason (I know, my position is supposed to be really easy to play but like idk man).</p>

<p>Bro, I can’t hit my Akali in my TFT game. I rolled like 60 gold looking for one Akali. I’m uncontested. HUH. It’s actually fine tho. Also, I have like 5 components… but it’s fine. Trust, yk…</p>

<p>Yeah, I kinda cook myself playing Re2 (idk which move). I mean, it’s a cool tactic, but I don’t know how I missed it. I mean, I should be able to see that even with very little time. Mb.</p>

<p>In conclusion, game 1 was fumbler turned scammer turned fumbler again.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-2-benjamin-cai-white-1---0">Game 2, Benjamin Cai White (1 - 0)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/YkIdtku7/QB2f5eJb" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>So, I am happy about this game because I won. But I am also not happy because I played very poorly.</p>

<p>I think Bc2 (move 14) is a really smart move to try to attack. This quiet move leads to the position I get. Of course, I throw it all away and fumble!</p>

<p>e5 (move 16) is such a stupid move that I have nothing else to really say other than that I just missed the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">FORWARD</code> knight move again. I’m cracked.</p>

<p>Also, Qg5 (move 33) was a blunder of a pawn but it somehow worked out? Before that, my opponent was somehow finding counterplay which was pretty impressive. Either way, I again threw with Bf2 (move 34) because Rf2 is somehow better? I thought that f6 was too troublesome to deal with but I guess not…</p>

<p>Either way, after losing the pawn, I only really have one thing to play for which is sacrificing everything and hoping for an attack. Computer likes my position but like I kinda liked my opponent’s position. Luckily, my opponent never played Qd8 which I thought would just let him stabilize. Because of that, I was able to scam a win…again.</p>

<p>So, in conclusion, game 2 was fumbler turned scammer.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-3-benjamin-cai-white-1---0">Game 3, Benjamin Cai White (1 - 0)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/YkIdtku7/Lp5UaNC2" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>Another f3 Nimzovitch. I kinda cook with this opening. But like, I also don’t know the theory that well. So I’m kinda cooked if c5 ever comes.</p>

<p>dxc5 (move 16) is the main <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">turning</code> point of this game. I sacrifice the exchange for an attack. Also mainly because the position where I don’t sac looks rather <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">painful</code> to play. Rxf6 (move 20) is actually a mistake. I thought that his king is getting cooked because of my bishops (which it is) but apparently just taking with the bishop is stronger. During the game before playing this move, I kind of realized this by calculating some weird king runs where he could just sacrifice all his material and still be up, but I thought that my attack was just too <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">strong</code>.</p>

<p>Of course, I don’t take the draw and am losing after e5 (move 25). Professional fumbler!</p>

<p>But I scam out a win with Nh5 (move 35) followed by Bf3 (move 38). To be honest, Nh5 was kind of just lucky as I didn’t even realize it stopped all the Queen checks. Luckily, I am a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">professional scammer</code> so I somehow end up up the exchange. I’m the goat.</p>

<p>In conclusion, this game was fumbler turned scammer.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-4-benjamin-cai-black-0---1">Game 4, Benjamin Cai Black (0 - 1)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/Qmf4TLNS/Tz43ud5x" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>So uh, I don’t know Rossolimo theory. I always play d5 (here it’s move 5), and then I tell myself that I will never play d5 again in the Rossolimo (then I play it again in a new game and the cycle repeats). Though if anybody prepping against me reads this, I just looked at Rossolimo theory so it won’t work. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Trust.</code></p>

<p>Kh7 (move 15), Rh8 (move 17), Kg8 (move 18) is an insane plan by me. I thought it was a good plan but in retrospect (hindsight bias), I was really stupid. Like, why would the h file ever open?</p>

<p>c4 (move 22) is where the game changes and I get advantage. To be frank, I don’t think I was ever losing that badly. I think his only chance at getting a significant attack would’ve been h5 after f6 (move 19). f6 is just a really nice move in my opinion. There’s a cool line with exd5, exd5, Qe6, Bf7, Qxc6, c4, and Queen is looking trapped. I actually didn’t see this and only saw that the Queen was in a bad spot after Qxc6.</p>

<p>Either way, after c6 (move 22), I just have a large advantage. I end up up the exchange with two minors for a rook (just like game 2) and I pretty easily convert (forgetting d3, move 40, where I just completely blunder a pawn).</p>

<p>So, in conclusion, this game was kind of a scammer moment since c4 comes out of nowhere from a cleanly worse position.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-5-benjamin-cai-black-0---1">Game 5, Benjamin Cai Black (0 - 1)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/YkIdtku7/Tigeny0z" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>Thank god, it’s a normal Sicilian (or normal in the sense that it’s not a moroxzy, grand prix, rossolimo, alapin, etc.). I get to play my theory! I somewhat understand the accelerated dragon position so it’s really easy to play for me!</p>

<p>Uh, my opponent makes a couple <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mistakes</code> in firstly playing f3 (move 7) followed by Qd2 (move 8) since it just gives me d5 for <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">free</code>. I play d5 and equalize pretty quickly. Then my opponent plays Bg5 (move 11) instead of say Bh6, and I’m pretty sure I’m the only one playing for a win.</p>

<p>A couple more mistakes and the game is over. This game had no scams nor no fumbles.</p>

<p>So, in conclusion, this game was a fine game by me (mainly because it was so short).</p>

<hr />
<p>End Results</p>

<p>I did <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code>, so uh, not that bad. I mean, I’m still pretty mad because I feel like I <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">100%</code> could’ve gone <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">5/5</code>. Fine tournament though. Hopefully I go to more.</p>

<p>Link to <a href="https://lichess.org/study/YkIdtku7/Tigeny0z">study</a> if you want it.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="cool-puzzle">Cool puzzle</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/ProfessionalFumbler-1.png" alt="asddf" title="ee" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Solve until either mate or draw or Black escapes, strange, strange position</code></p>]]></content><author><name>Benjamin Cai</name><email>main@benjamincai.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This tournament is probably the last one I go to for a long time. The unique point about this tournament was that I did not play all that up, meaning that most people I played were below me in rating. I actually don’t really like that. It’s kinda weird to play people under. I like being the underdog! Having the handicap makes it much easier because then even if you fail, it’s expected. I think I could’ve won all my first game and then I would’ve had a chance to go 5/5 but it is what it is yk. Man, that first game really makes me disappointed in myself. I had the much better position but then I hard threw. Is what it is. That’s why you don’t go low on time.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/ProfessionalFumbler1.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/ProfessionalFumbler1.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Standard Tournament</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/04/A-Standard-Tournament/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Standard Tournament" /><published>2025-08-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-08-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/04/A-Standard-Tournament</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/04/A-Standard-Tournament/"><![CDATA[<p>Yoooo. Uh, mb bro. Might’ve neglected to post. Oh well. I’m still better than those people who take a year to post!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The fact that I am <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">alive</code> at this moment is a miracle, because after this first game I was ready to go the ocean and never come back!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I know I’ve quoted this before, but it’s actually a fire quote! Oh wait, wrong one. You see, I just copy pasted the old tournament <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.md</code> file, but I did want to talk about a cool quote…</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If I don’t kill myself tonight I will live a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">thousand years</code></p>
  <ul>
    <li>Ivan Sokolov, Chess guy that does chess things chess</li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>

<p>Fire quote.</p>

<p>I did pretty bad at this tournament. But honestly, I feel pretty great. That might be because this tournament happened like a month ago, but it might also just be because I <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">literally don't care</code>. Nah…nvm, doesn’t really work. Sometimes works when Hikaru does it though.</p>

<p>Uh, first game was pretty not perfect. Mainly because I somehow messed up a really nice attack. Oh well. I am kind of a professional fumbler. Actually… I think I fumbled all my games. Very sad.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-1-benjamin-cai-white-05---05">Game 1 Benjamin Cai White (0.5 - 0.5)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/Qmf4TLNS/32BEmbI7" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>Yeah, I kinda suck. I played this game a month ago. I still regret it. At least, I scammed out a draw… Professional fumbler Benjamin Cai.</p>

<p>Also, my friend said it’s probably not good that I put people’s names here, and he’s probably right. So, no more names. I’m too lazy to remove the old ones though. If I ever become famous I will though. No <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">free</code> clout.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-2-benjamin-cai-black-1---0">Game 2, Benjamin Cai Black (1 - 0)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/Qmf4TLNS/2sKHM2hX" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>A true Benjamin Cai moment. I suck at chess. Oh well. Will probably be fine. Talked with the guy after. He was pretty chill. He was not as young as me though. But he was very chill. Not much to say about the game other than I hard threw. I don’t even know how me and my opponent analyzed. Like what is there to analyze? I just lost horrendously.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-3-benjamin-cai-black-1---0">Game 3, Benjamin Cai Black (1 - 0)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/Qmf4TLNS/4PTPUfdv" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>Yeah, this one hurt cause I was kinda cooking. Computer says draw but like any human is gonna wanna play as black. Oh well. Is what it is.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-4-benjamin-cai-white-1---0">Game 4, Benjamin Cai White (1 - 0)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/Qmf4TLNS/Tz43ud5x" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>So, this is the start of the games that I stopped having good notation for. The other three games I put in as soon as I finished playing. So those have pretty good comments tbh. Oh shoot, I haven’t done a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">red</code> thing. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mb</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mb</code>.</p>

<p>Anyways, uh, reading my handwriting was quite fun. Sometimes, when I notate chess games while playing, I forget to write a move so then I get like messed up and I write one move as two so that I reset back to the correct white and black. Like, yk, how chess notation switches between white and black. So if you miss one move, you’re <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">offset</code>. I’ll write two moves to correct that. Problem is sometimes, if my handwriting is really bad, that gets confusing. Yeah, I could not read my own handwriting. I’m <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cracked</code>!</p>

<p>Fine game, though, like always, I fumbled. They should honestly just call me the fumbler. Idk, good thought man. I scammed a win like how I scammed a draw that first game.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-5-benjamin-cai-black-05---05">Game 5, Benjamin Cai Black (0.5 - 0.5)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/Qmf4TLNS/nqEdkGAQ" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>Not much to say. Very, very boring game. Literally nothing to analyze. Couple <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sacs</code> that were possible throughout but my opponent and I both missed them, so is what it is. Draw is better than a loss… though the difference between a win and a draw is infinitely greater than the difference between a draw and a loss. Man, it really just is what it is.</p>

<hr />
<p>End Results</p>

<p>I did <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code>, so uh, really bad. But uh, it’s fine. Probably the last chess tournament I go to in a long time if I’m being realistic. But like, there’s still hope for <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">gm</code> yk. Nah, not really. I’m too bad at chess. I don’t even think there’s hope for <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2000</code> anymore. Is what it is though.</p>

<p>Link to <a href="https://lichess.org/study/zMyqTta6/lbKKtqQy">study</a> if you want it.</p>

<hr />

<p>Uh, no photos. Not much to say there. Every time I go to a tournament, I feel very alone. Oh well, is what it is. Hans Niemann does the thing where he streams about how lonely he is. That’s why he’s my goat. Not like sad alone though. I’m like happy alone yk. I don’t know.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="no-puzzle-cause-im-washed-now">No puzzle cause I’m washed now</h2>]]></content><author><name>Benjamin Cai</name><email>main@benjamincai.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yoooo. Uh, mb bro. Might’ve neglected to post. Oh well. I’m still better than those people who take a year to post!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/AStandardTournament1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/AStandardTournament1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Best Tournament Yet?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/My-Best-Tournament-Yet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Best Tournament Yet?" /><published>2025-06-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-06-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/My-Best-Tournament-Yet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/26/My-Best-Tournament-Yet/"><![CDATA[<p>I have gone a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">long(?)</code> time without success at a chess tournament. I mean, that definition is rather relative, but for me, I think I’ve gone about a full year without a truly successful tournament. I’ve had tournaments where I haven’t been completely droven into the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ground</code>, but I haven’t had any for at least a year where I’ve felt confident (and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">good</code>) at chess. The last tournament where I had success was the 2024 Universal Chess Open U2000<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">(?)</code> where I got 2nd place (+ a lot of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">money</code>!). Hans Niemann played at that tournament. I saw him. It was quite the experience.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The fact that I am <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">alive</code> at this moment is a miracle, because after this first game I was ready to go the ocean and never come back!</p>

  <p>I wanted to lose as quickly as possible, so I could go back to my hotel room, turn the lights off, order some delivery, watch <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Netflix and numb the pain</code> until the next game. I think my Uber Eats has gone up to 1000 dollars for this event. I have been indulging and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">numbing the pain</code> with 1000 dollar Uber Eats.</p>
  <ul>
    <li>Quote by one <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Hans Niemann</code> (most chess player quote I’ve ever seen)</li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>

<p>Either way, the point I wanted to make was that I was on some level of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">tilt</code> for chess. I mean, I’ve never practiced or studied in any full capacity for chess, instead just kinda playing for fun, but it certainly does not feel good to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">lose</code>. Actually, for like a month before this tournament, I was engaging in a lot of chess: playing <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">rapid</code> games, analyzing, and doing tons of chess <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">puzzles</code>. For me, chess is kinda a way to feel productive while waiting for something to happen or when I’m nervous. Idk. I played some chess right before graduation for some reasons. And I will leave it at that. Anyways, this was a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">four game, one day</code> tournament (so pretty short in comparison to the three day or two day seven round tournaments).</p>

<p>I came into the first game realizing that I was playing against somebody who coached me for, I think, two weeks when I just got back into chess and was maybe <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1100 USCF</code>. I was underrated though.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-1-benjamin-cai-v-daniel-hung-1---0">Game 1, Benjamin Cai v Daniel Hung (1 - 0)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/zMyqTta6/7AC0pEnU" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>A rather sad game. Definitely could’ve been played better by me. The sad part is just how close I was to a perfect game. Move 24 (g4) is a huge mistake. Like, Jesus, just play Kh2. For some reason, I was in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">attack-attack-attack</code> mindset, so I ignored common sense. The craziest part is that I saw his ideas with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Qd5</code> and pinning my queen with his rook, but for some reason, I thought – looks pretty <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cool</code>, down to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">try</code>.</p>

<p>I wanted to talk to my opponent after but, at the same time, felt kind of bad, so I did not do anything (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pro</code> extrovert).</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-2-benjamin-cai-v-baron-t-niu-0---1">Game 2, Benjamin Cai v Baron T Niu (0 - 1)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/zMyqTta6/6K3o7hCb" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>Uh, quite a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sad</code> game. I think I was still somewhat on tilt the first two games. I played really poorly this game. Some absolutely abysmal follow ups to sacrifices and just no drive to fight for counterplay. Move 15 (a3) could’ve been replaced with d5 and I would’ve been <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ding chilling</code>. Surprisingly, I still feel really great about this tournament even though I lost this game. I also think that’s because my opponent was rated so far above me (2200 USCF) to the point where, even though I think I could’ve put up a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">much better</code> fight, it’s fine that I didn’t.</p>

<p>I also talked to this guy after the game. It was very fun talking to him. He’s also like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">CS adjacent</code> but at, I think, CMU (pretty smart guy). It’s kinda sad to think how <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">difficult</code> chess will be to maintain in college though. Hopefully, I actually start practicing and studying to get better!</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-3-matthew-raudaskoski-v-benjamin-cai-0---1">Game 3, Matthew Raudaskoski v Benjamin Cai (0 - 1)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/zMyqTta6/YNACdYbP" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>I’m just now realizing that by posting chess to my website, my opponents that <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">prep</code> are going to have a much easier time. Welp, hopefully I can just <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">outskill</code> them. Actually, the better idea might be getting so good at chess that I can play <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">any opening</code>! Yeah, that’s not happening. I’m pretty washed and bad at chess.</p>

<p>This game was <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">decent</code> by me. Yeah, there were quite a few mistakes, but is what it is. I need to practice more chess. The opening was entirely new territory for me, but I should’ve just stuck to the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Sicilian Khan</code> setup. Immediately after playing Move 6 (Qb6), I realized a6 was so much <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">better</code>. a6 is a move in the Khan setup, should’ve just followed the limited opening theory I know.</p>

<p>Also, you have no idea how tempted I was to take on f2 with my Queen on Move 7. Yes, it’s <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">completely losing</code>. But…idk man, looks cool or something? Still can’t believe I missed the complexities in Bc5. I spent a long time looking at that move. But for some reason, I never fully explored Ne3.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="game-4-kai-zhou-lan-v-benjamin-cai-0---1">Game 4, Kai Zhou Lan v Benjamin Cai (0 - 1)</h1>
<div class="lichess-embed-container">
  <iframe src="https://lichess.org/study/embed/zMyqTta6/lbKKtqQy" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>I’m very happy, obviously — as happy as you can be beating a little kid.</p>

<p>Yeah, it’s funnier when <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Magnus</code> says it. Very nice game though. I liked my tactical prowess here. Also, I liked that one of my coach’s ideas (a5) actually worked. I’d been telling him that a5 looked <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">stupid</code> (because it does) but it actually worked. Crazy. Some very nice Knight <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jumps</code>, and I calculated basically to the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">end</code> from Move 11.</p>

<p>I do feel bad about this game though. I am very sad and often tilt after losing chess games in that kinda way so I do hope my opponent gets over it quick.</p>

<hr />
<p>End Results</p>

<p><img src="/assets/postImages/MyBestTournamentYet1.png" alt="asdf" title="DD" /></p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Very bad tiebreaks</code></p>

<p>I am quite satisfied with my performance. Tournament was played on 6/21/2025. I also grew 100 USCF points which is pretty damn good for just one tournament. Here is the lichess <a href="https://lichess.org/study/zMyqTta6/lbKKtqQy">study</a> if you wanted to see it.</p>

<hr />

<p>I unfortunately did not take any photos at this tournament. I feel like I am regretting more and more when I don’t take <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">photos</code> at places in general. Perhaps part of getting older. Idk. I talked to a lot of cool people this tournament. Actually, that’s a strange pattern for tournaments where I’m <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">successful</code>. Another strange pattern is succeeding at tournaments when I’m also getting over something in my life. Wait, that’s actually true. That’s <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">crazy</code>. This was a much shorter tournament than the 2024 Universal Open U2000, but the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">patterns</code> are still the same. I’m also not sure if it’s talking to other tournament players that makes me win games or if it’s me winning games that makes me want to talk to other tournament players. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Strange</code>.</p>

<p>Anyways, as is tradition, I will leave you with a nice little chess position.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="calculate-until-mate">Calculate until mate</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/MyBestTournamentYet2.png" alt="asddf" title="ee" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Not really all that tactical a position, but like it is a member of the set of all possible chess positions.</code></p>]]></content><author><name>Benjamin Cai</name><email>main@benjamincai.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have gone a long(?) time without success at a chess tournament. I mean, that definition is rather relative, but for me, I think I’ve gone about a full year without a truly successful tournament. I’ve had tournaments where I haven’t been completely droven into the ground, but I haven’t had any for at least a year where I’ve felt confident (and good) at chess. The last tournament where I had success was the 2024 Universal Chess Open U2000(?) where I got 2nd place (+ a lot of money!). Hans Niemann played at that tournament. I saw him. It was quite the experience.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/MyBestTournamentYet1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/MyBestTournamentYet1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stressful Summer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/24/Stressful-Summer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stressful Summer" /><published>2025-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/24/Stressful-Summer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/24/Stressful-Summer/"><![CDATA[<p>In my last post, I started off with saying that spring semester of senior year was simultaneously the most <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">relaxing</code> time and the most <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">productive</code> time of my year (reading that in my head, I now realize that those are not <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">mutually exclusive</code>). Either way, I think I most felt that way due to the stress of the summer right before that. The simplest way to illustrate this is in the schedule I had during <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">July</code>.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I very much want to preface, though, by saying that, even though that summer was extremely <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">stressful</code>, I also would not have changed anything. 
I learned and developed so many skills that I very much value now.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Anyways, during the weekdays on July, I had an internship that had me wake up at <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">7:30 AM</code> (frankly, not all that early considering when school starts) and getting home at <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">5:30 PM</code>. Don’t get me wrong – I am invariably grateful for the opportunities and learning experiences I had during that internship, but it was also the first <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">full</code> 9-5 (though really an <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">8-5</code>) that I’d worked with real responsibilities. Plus, I also did a lot of work on internship projects at home, which looking back (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">hindsight bias</code>), was probably a major stressor. On Saturday, I’d wake up at <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">6:00 AM</code> and volunteer at St. David’s Hospital until <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3:00 PM</code>. Again, I want to make myself clear, these experiences were fantastic – the people I met and the activities I partook(<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">?</code>) in were great! However, at the same time, it was the most <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">filled up</code> my schedule had ever been (beyond school, which, at a certain point, stops being stressful). After <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3:00 PM</code>, I’d teach and manage a small chess club a friend and I started until about <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">5:00 PM</code> (again, the most fun I’ve perhaps had in a long time, but still very much the longest I’ve ever had to be <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">on</code>).</p>

<p>As I’m writing this, I’m realizing that perhaps it’s not very interesting for me to explain why each of these events were great while <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">concurrently</code> ‘complaining’ about the stress they caused, but that was the reality I had. Between <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">7:00 PM</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">8:30</code> PM, I’d teach a private chess class. Sunday was a lot of chess. We had a chess club meeting some days as well as the afternoon consisting of chess classes. That being said, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Sunday</code> was the most relaxing day within those weeks. It would be the day I’d be waiting for – mainly because I knew I’d have time to practice piano, read, and review the (very fun!) <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">math</code> that I was learning about at my internship.</p>

<p>I tried to sprinkle those things in between the other times I had, but frankly, most days, I was way too tired to do anything other than just watch <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YouTube</code>, or at best, go down some <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Wikipedia rabbit hole</code>. Some weekends, I’d also go to competitions or tournaments as well, which was very interesting to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">fit in</code>.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="where-i-volunteered-at-st-davids">Where I volunteered at St. David’s</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/StressfulSummer2.png" alt="stsdfs" title="HospitalFrontDesk" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">I'm not one to really take pictures (kinda a regret now, my friend took some photos with me here), but I never really did</code></p>

<p>Quite the stressful time looking back. But also, I kinda don’t get how I was so stressed. Like, honestly, just <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">keep your head down and work like K does</code>. That was not as funny as I thought it would be!</p>

<p>I mean, looking back, I gained a lot from being so stressed during summer. In fact, I think I probably could’ve grown more by being <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">more</code> stressed! The fact is that…what doesn’t kill you makes you stronger…I’m sorry. No, but it’s also kind of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">true</code>! I think, being forced to pursue all those <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">different</code> things, have such <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">little</code> free time, and also get a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">full</code> 8 hours each night (which I force myself to do), plus maintain my <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">prior</code> skills, develops something that can’t be given by <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">genetics</code> or even <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">hard work</code>.</p>

<p>I think a lot of life is based on <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">luck</code>, not talent or hard work. Surprisingly, who you’re friends with is oftentimes just <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">chance</code>. I think I got <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">lucky</code> getting this experience right before senior year.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="my-full-schedule">My full schedule</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/StressfulSummer1.png" alt="gc" title="Google Calendar" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">I don't really use calendars (for some reason, I think I'll get a better memory by just memorizing what I have to do)</code></p>

<p>So much was learned. Mostly <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">R</code>, but also some other stuff. Yeah, I’m kinda running out of things to say. I somehow found time to do <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">activities</code> with friends like climbing and going to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">places</code> (I do not know how). Anyways, I will leave you guys with a very nice chess position (plus, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">main@benjamincai.com</code> works as an email now! (cloudflare was surprisingly easy, 17 year old me was <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">stupid</code>, nothing like 18 year old me who is very <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">smart</code>)).</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="nice-little-position-from-a-recent-tournament-on-june-6-2025-v2">Nice little position from a recent tournament on June 6, 2025 (v2)</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/StressfulSummer3.png" alt="asdf" title="Nice little position from a tournament on June 6, 2025" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Look at ts. Beautiful. So goddamn beautiful. I feel bad for my opponent because I've been in his exact position. I hope he gets over it quick. Also Black to win in like 4 moves. Beautiful. Knights.</code></p>]]></content><author><name>Benjamin Cai</name><email>main@benjamincai.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my last post, I started off with saying that spring semester of senior year was simultaneously the most relaxing time and the most productive time of my year (reading that in my head, I now realize that those are not mutually exclusive). Either way, I think I most felt that way due to the stress of the summer right before that. The simplest way to illustrate this is in the schedule I had during July.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/StressfulSummer1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/StressfulSummer1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The story of the old site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/22/oldSite/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The story of the old site" /><published>2025-06-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-06-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/22/oldSite</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/22/oldSite/"><![CDATA[<p>Spring semester of senior year in high school was a very interesting time for me. It was undoubtedly somehow the most relaxed period of my high school career, and yet also simultaneously the most productive<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">(?)</code> I’d felt yet. I hadn’t really decided that strongly what I wanted to study in college coming into senior year, so it was a bit of a rush watching everybody around me talk about college applications that first week back. I’d been considering computer science as a major, but frankly, I wasn’t much set on it.</p>

<p>Looking back, the main reason I was considering computer science was pretty stupid (most of my friends who already graduated went into it), but it was still the main factor nonetheless. Also, after thinking about it, the college that I would most likely be attending due to cost, location, and relative prestige, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">UT Austin</code>, was most well-renowned for computer science. So, I decided pretty quickly that I would be applying for computer science.</p>

<p>Of course, that came with a whole host of other issues. Computer science is notoriously competitive, which was certainly not very fun to think about. I’d been fortunate enough to be in the top 6% of my graduating class (which guarantees a spot at UT Austin), but everybody around me had been mentioning how that didn’t actually guarantee a major (ie. I would be admitted to UT Austin, but not to computer science). Either way, I wanted to try to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">boost</code> up my resume as much as I could before submitting college applications. I’d done some computer science stuff before, but honestly, it was nowhere near what other people had done. So, for those couple weeks before <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">October</code> (which was when UT Austin’s deadline was), I embarked on a lot of different projects to, perhaps unhealthily, grow my resume. Don’t get me wrong – the process of learning about all those different fields and thinking programmatically was extremely rewarding and probably useful, but I still think that the primary cause of why I did all that <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">(resume projects)</code> was not good.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="cloudflare-attack-moment">Cloudflare Attack Moment</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/oldSite1.png" alt="Yeah, I had this turned on always for some reason" title="Cloudflare Attack Moment" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Yeah, I had this turned on always for some reason</code></p>

<p>Either way, eventually, I saw a really cool personal site (forgot whose tho) and, pretty flippantly, decided that I wanted something similar. So, I spent a weekend (with a lot of help from certain AI tools) building the html and css for the old site. The one painful part after I’d finished was writing <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">blog posts</code> (I’d heard of like Jekyll and stuff, but frankly, I didn’t think I was knowledgable enough in computer science to understand how those site generators worked). I’d learned <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bash</code> the summer before senior year from an internship (great experience) and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">daily driving Linux</code> (I’m a nerd, shut up), and I’d been writing some useful scripts + productivity stuff for my own Linux setup so I decided to take a stab at probably the most impressive part of the entire old site: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">the blog post generator</code>.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="analytics-make-me-feel-good">Analytics make me feel good</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/oldSite2.png" alt="Watching ts is my addiction" title="Analytics make me feel good" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Watching ts is my strange addiction</code></p>

<p>In hindsight, the code and actual generation is done really poorly. I mean, there’s no image support, and I have to manually type <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;br&gt;</code> for a new line (not good), but it worked for my setup (which was very poor <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">center-aligned</code> blog posts, nothing like what I have now, which are very poor <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">left-aligned</code> blog posts). I think, at that point in time, I was just so captured by all the little things that programming could replace, so even something as trivial as a .txt reader was fascinating. The idea that I could navigate to a blogPosts directory, write a .txt file, run a script, and then have a .html file corresponding to a blog post now on the site, was really damn cool.</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="k">if</span> <span class="o">[[</span> <span class="o">!</span> <span class="nt">-f</span> <span class="s2">"blog.html"</span> <span class="o">]]</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="k">then
    </span><span class="nb">echo</span> <span class="s2">"NO blog.html"</span>
<span class="k">else
    </span><span class="nb">sed</span> <span class="nt">-i</span> <span class="s2">"/&lt;!-- REMOVE BLOG POST --&gt;/,/&lt;</span><span class="se">\/</span><span class="s2">a&gt;/d"</span> blog.html
    <span class="nb">sed</span> <span class="nt">-i</span> <span class="s2">"/&lt;!-- INSERT BLOG POSTS HERE1 --&gt;/i &lt;!-- REMOVE BLOG POST --&gt;"</span> blog.html
    <span class="nb">sed</span> <span class="nt">-i</span> <span class="s2">"/&lt;!-- INSERT BLOG POSTS HERE1 --&gt;/i </span><span class="nv">$blog_link</span><span class="s2">"</span> blog.html
    <span class="nb">sed</span> <span class="nt">-i</span> <span class="s2">"/&lt;!-- INSERT BLOG POSTS HERE2 --&gt;/a </span><span class="nv">$blog_link</span><span class="s2">"</span> blog.html
<span class="k">fi</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>This part, which is just changing the links on the blog page took way too long to build. I was not very good at bash.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="this-never-worked">This never worked</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/oldSite3.png" alt="One of my friends(?) tried emailing me at that link (main@benjamincai.com), I never set it up" title="This never worked" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">One of my friends(?) tried emailing me at that link (main@benjamincai.com), I never set it up</code></p>

<p>It’s kinda sad to part with the old site because, on some level, it represents parting with high school (lots of people <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">strongly</code> suggested with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">strong language</code> that center-aligned text was not very good-looking + one person once commented on how interestingly I wrote the about me (which I’d been waiting for somebody to comment on)). At the same time though, is what it is. This new <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Jekyll</code> site looks way better, mostly because <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cvless</code> carries, but still, I digress.</p>

<p>This post came out pretty sad. The others probably won’t. Here’s to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">hoping</code>. I mean, really, here’s to knowing (because I know they won’t be sad!). I’ll leave you with chess.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="nice-little-position-from-a-recent-tournament-on-june-6-2025">Nice little position from a recent tournament on June 6, 2025</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/postImages/oldSite4.png" alt="(I mean what I played blunders the entire position, should've just played Kh2 instead of g4 and kept my +5, but like still a nice position, but oh well, Rxf5 was too enticing) Actually, that's 100% the wrong mindset, I should've played Kh2" title="Nice little position from a tournament on June 6, 2025" />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">(I mean what I played blunders the entire position, should've just played Kh2 instead of g4 and kept my +5, but like still a nice position, but oh well, Rxf5 was too enticing) Actually, that's 100% the wrong mindset, I should've played Kh2</code></p>]]></content><author><name>Benjamin Cai</name><email>main@benjamincai.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spring semester of senior year in high school was a very interesting time for me. It was undoubtedly somehow the most relaxed period of my high school career, and yet also simultaneously the most productive(?) I’d felt yet. I hadn’t really decided that strongly what I wanted to study in college coming into senior year, so it was a bit of a rush watching everybody around me talk about college applications that first week back. I’d been considering computer science as a major, but frankly, I wasn’t much set on it.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/oldSite1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postImages/oldSite1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>